my-wardrobe.com 2015-10-10

# Help | UK | THE OUTNET

We respect the privacy rights of our online visitors and recognise the importance of protecting your personal information. We have adopted a corporate wide Privacy Policy that guides how we collect, store, and use the information that you provide us with. 

The following information is provided by THE OUTNET to enable our online visitors to be fully informed of our Privacy Policies. By visiting THE OUTNET, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions.

If you are under 16, we require that you inform a parent or guardian about THE OUTNET's Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions as well as requiring their consent to the Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions before registering with THE OUTNET or placing an order with THE OUTNET.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to websites maintained by other companies or organisations to which we link. THE OUTNET is not responsible for any personal information you submit to third parties via our website. Please ensure that you read the Privacy Policy of such other companies or organisations before submitting your details. 

  * [What personal information do we collect from  
you and how? ]()
    * THE OUTNET collects personal information in several ways when you place an order or register for a service offered by THE OUTNET. By registering, you are consenting to the collection of your personal data. If an order is placed with us, we need to hold personal information including your name, email address, phone numbers, home address, shipping and credit card billing address(es) so that we can process and fulfil your order. We also collect and record the card details of registered customers to make shopping at THE OUTNET even quicker. Saved card details will never be shared with third parties and will only be used to process your order, using our payment partner's systems. More details on saved card details can be found in our FAQs. Additionally we may also obtain information as a result of authentication or identity checks. Sometimes we may ask for your telephone number. This number may be given to our courier for delivery services. These details allow us to process your order and to let you know the status of your order.

In addition, our Live Chat provider stores all chat conversations for 13 months. These transcripts are only accessed by THE OUTNET for training purposes so we can enhance the service we provide. To receive a copy of your chat conversation simply request this when exiting Live Chat or contact our customer care team by emailing [customercare@theoutnet.com](mailto:customercare@theoutnet.com). Alternatively, you can call 0800 011 4250 (UK) or +44 330 022 4250 (from a mobile or internationally).

    * Our site uses cookies (very small files that are sent by us to your computer or other access device) which we can access when you visit our site in future.

There are four types of cookies:

**Website functionality cookies**

These cookies enable you to browse the website and use our features such as shopping baskets and wish lists

**Website analytics cookies**

We use these cookies to measure and analyse how our customers use the website. This allows us to continuously improve our website and your shopping experience.

**Customer preference cookies**

When browsing or shopping online, the website will remember preferences you make (for example your user name, language or location). This makes your browsing experience simpler, easier and more personal to you.

**Targeting cookies or advertising cookies**

These cookies are used to deliver adverts relevant to you. In addition, they limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as helping us measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns. 

**By using our website you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device and access them when you visit the site in the future.**

If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to the help and support area on your internet browser for instructions on how to locate the file or directory that stores cookies.

Information on deleting or controlling cookies is available at [www.AboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). Please note that by deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our site.

  * [How this information may be used, including   
anyone it might be shared with ]()
    * THE OUTNET may use your personal information for the processing of orders, payments and to provide you with a personalized shopping experience. We will also use your details to fulfil and deliver your orders and manage your account. Personal information that you provide may be disclosed to a credit reference or fraud prevention agency, which may keep a record of that information. Your personal information may also be shared with other trading divisions within The Net-a-Porter Group Limited. Where there is a legal obligation to do so, we may disclose your information to any relevant regulatory body or pursuant to a court order.

We may also use your personal information to send you marketing updates but only ever in accordance with your preferences (as detailed in the next section). We do not sell your details to third party marketing companies.

We do collate information about site traffic, sales, most wanted lists, and other commercial information which we may pass on to third parties but this information does not include any information which can identify you personally.

Finally, we may use your personal information for our internal marketing and demographic studies, together with non-personal data to monitor customer patterns so we can consistently improve our site design to better meet our visitors' needs. 

From time to time THE OUTNET may employ third party business partners to collect personal information on THE OUTNET's behalf. THE OUTNET may also share your data with third party business partners to provide you with targeted advertising. In such cases, these third parties will be subject to confidentiality agreements and instructed by THE OUTNET to comply with applicable data protection law.

    * When you register, you will be given the option to opt-out of subscribing to our regular update service which will send you: 

(i) Email alerts for new products, features, enhancements, special offers, upgrade opportunities, contests, events of interest, and one-off marketing promotions. 

(ii) Direct mail alerts for new products, features, enhancements, special offers, upgrade opportunities, contests, events of interest, and one-off marketing promotions. 

Marketing communications you subscribe to will only be sent by The Net-a-Porter Group Limited.

At all times, we will offer you the opportunity to unsubscribe out of any service or update to which you have subscribed, if you change your mind. Any e-mail we send you will contain an easy automated unsubscribe link so that you can opt-out of that particular mailshot. Simply follow the indications in the e-mail. Alternatively you can change your email preferences or opt out of all emails by logging into My Account. To opt out of the direct mail service or updates, please contact Customer Care on 0800 011 4250 (UK) or +44 330 022 4250 (from a mobile or internationally). Alternatively you can send an email to [customercare@theoutnet.com](mailto:customercare@theOutnet.com). 

  * [How you can access and if necessary, change the personal information THE OUTNET maintains]()
    * If for any reason you are concerned that the personal information held by THE OUTNET is not correct, please visit the website and, after logging into the site using the 'Sign In' menu on the home page, your personal information will be made available for review and change in the 'My Account' section. Only you or, upon your request, a Customer Care advisor, may access your personal data from the website using your password and User ID. Information may be changed online within My Account, Address Book, and My Emails. You can change or delete saved credit card details each time you make a purchase. You will also be able to delete saved credit card details by adding or editing a shipping/billing address. If you prefer, you may contact us by email at [customercare@theoutnet.com](mailto:customercare@theOutnet.com) and we will amend your personal details.

    * We will use our best endeavours to maintain appropriate safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of the information you have provided us with. When you place an order or access your account information, we use a Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption which encrypts your information before it is sent to us to protect it from unauthorised use. In addition, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that third party business partners to whom we transfer any data will provide sufficient protection of that personal information.

  * [Where and how to ask questions or file   
complaints]()
    * If you require further information about our Privacy Policy, please go to the help section of the web site where frequently asked questions (FAQ's) are answered, if you require more information please go to the Contact Us section of the web site and send an e mail to the relevant department of THE OUTNET. To talk to Customer Care please call 0800 011 4250 (UK) or +44 330 022 4250 (from a mobile or internationally) or write to: c/o Data Protection Officer, The Net-a-Porter Group Limited, 1 The Village Offices, Westfield London Shopping Centre, Ariel Way, London, W12 7GF.
